Ajay Chawada

Experience: 3.5+ years Role: Frontend developer (React JS / React Native)
Location: Mumbai Contact: +91 7021375254 | ajaychawda1997@gmail.com

Looking for a position as front-end developer in growth-oriented company where I can utilize my skills to the company's advantage, as well as develop my own skills and career.

Technical Skills

Languages: JavaScript, React JS, React Native, Sass, HTML, CSS & TypeScript

Tools / Software: Visual studio code, Android studio, Git hub, Git lab, Jira, XCode, Figma & Firebase

Popular NPM Package: react-router-dom, react-redux, react-saga, styled-component, axios, react-query etc.

Professional Experience

Codemonk (Elvago technology)

Sept 2021 – Present

GreytHR (HRMS Mobile application - React Native)

The App offers productivity tools for better delivery of HR services such as pay roll, attendance management, leave management, helpdesk to **15K+ small and medium businesses across 150+ cities**.

Google Analytics

Integrated Google Analytics for tracking more than 1 million user's behaviour such as screen tracking, campaigns and traffic sources (APK download source), company URL, users by country, state, mobile platform (iOS / android), average user engagement time etc.

Feeds

- Implemented "Create a post" feature with text, links and attachments (supports docs, image & gif)
- Implemented functionalities such as scrolling pagination, delete post, like / dislike post, add / delete comment & "New post available" feature.
- Filter the feeds based on latest interacted & most recent feed, view comments / liked by users and download attachment attached to post.

<u>Helpdesk</u>

- The Helpdesk module allow employee to raise requests for their queries from different categories and the reviewers review the raised tickets in order to resolve them.
- Implemented functionalities such as raise a new request, view pending and resolved requests with scrolling pagination.
- Reviewer can view, comment, resolve, close and forward the request.

Quick-links

Add / remove / update quick links based on a user's priority & easily switch between screens

Also worked on login flow, **performance optimization**, attendance override & document center module.

Metasys software Jul 2019 – Sept 2021

Timesheet (React JS)

A web application for project members to record their time usage each day

- Converted class components into functional components.
- Implemented Add, update, delete a record.
- Added Different types of employee reports with filter and search and export to excel feature (Billable hours, non-billable hours, filter based on employee or project).
- Improved the performance and implemented responsive design.

IBC App (React Native)

A package tracking app for IBC staff to perform day-to-day operations on their courier business.

- **Published app** on App Store and Play Store, Created common re-useable components etc.
- Implemented Sign up form, Company police Screens, saved card UI, tracking details etc.

I also worked on 10mins Question web App (React js) and Analogic mobile App (React native).

Personal Project

SNKRS (React) Live app: https://ajay24897.github.io/snkrs/

Shoe e-commerce app developed with React, Sass, Google Firebase authentication & Firestore

- Stored product information and base64 image in Firestore database.
- Authentication (sign up, login & logout).
- Rendered product list for men's, women's and unisex category with scrolling pagination & nested routing.
- Implemented "Add to Cart", checkout, share link of product on WhatsApp and download shoe image functionality.
- Image carousel, CSS animation, transitions & zoom-in product image on hover (zoomed image relative to cursor). Responsive design as per different device sizes.

Education

• B.Tech in Electronics and telecommunication (Mumbai university)

Jun 2015 - May 2019

Certifications & Achievements

- React Hacker Rank https://www.hackerrank.com/certificates/ece190b93d41
- JavaScript Hacker Rank https://www.hackerrank.com/certificates/81de0e66208a
- Created and deployed 2 React native packages on NPM

Hobbies

Learning new library and building projects, trekking and listing music